# **Pre-Qualified of Enumerators for Somaliland regions**

Saeed Mohamed saedxabo@gmail.com +252 63 4026056

Skype: saed-xabo

Sha'ab Area, Hargeisa, Somaliland

The Development Fund job.developmentfund@gmail.com Masallah area, Hargeisa, Somaliland

### **DEAR HIRING MANAGER**

I am applying for the enumerator position at The Development Fund that you have posted on the Somali jobs page. The attached resume has a complete look at my work experience and training but here are a few highlights of my career so far.

I have a bachelor's degree in Software engineering and almost six months of work AME data analyst at ACTED(Agency for technical cooperation). My responsibilities included Track records of scanning the assigned areas to collect demographic information for record and reporting purposes. Extensive know-how of developing and interpreting surveys, questions, and leading interviewees through interview procedures to derive good data. Able to identify and resolve demographic data discrepancies and inconsistencies. Special talent for reviewing information for completeness and accuracy. Also, I have good knowledge in the data management tools, and GIS tools; I was also responsible for installing and upgrading network infrastructures like LANs and WANs, Keep track of any IT equipment, maintain the local office IT inventory list up-to-date, observe any IT equipment expiry dates on a daily, monthly, and yearly basis and take upgrading measures in time, and provide support for network users.

I have experience configuring hardware and software tools, tracking inventory, and developing contingency plans to use in the event of a network failure. My experience also includes operating office equipment such as copiers, processing mail, preparing other office management tools for the organization.

I have the ability to keep accurate documentation for all services I provide and I always offer a friendly and professional work environment. I have excellent organizational and multitasking skills and the ability to work independently or with a team. I possess excellent research skills, the ability to evaluate and solve problems, and the ability to make good decisions when working under pressure. I would like to meet with you in person to discuss this position in more detail and how I can be a great addition to your team. Thank you for your the time to read my application.

Respectfully, Saeed Mohamed

### SAEED MOHAMED MOUSE

+252 63 4026056 saedxabo@gmail.com saed-xabo Hargeisa, Somaliland

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

A proactive and fast learning individual seeking the opportunity for professional experience in an Information tech; that allows me to develop and expand my ability, knowledge, skills, and experience to help the organization achieve business goals while sticking to vision, mission, and values

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## JAN 2020 - JULY 2020, AGENCY FOR TECHNICAL COOPRATION, AME DATABASE INTERN

- Performing data cleaning liaises with field staff.
- Checking the quality of data submitted by the field staff.
- Verifying the data accuracy collected during the assessment.
- Cleaning data during the assessment and flagging any issues.
- extract queries, figures, and reports from the database.
- Creating Maps in Geographical Information Systems.

## MAY 2019 - OCT 2019, AWAYS DEVELOPER, REMOTE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- Develops information systems by designing, developing, and
- installing software solutions.
- Determines operational feasibility by evaluating analysis, problem definition,
- requirements, solution development, and proposed solutions.
- Knowledge of computer systems and the latest technologies.

### FEB 2019 - DEC 2019, DARYEEL TECHNOLOGY, ICT ASSISTANT

- Creating all types of visual design work including reports, publications, posters, brochures, flyers, logos, banners, and multi-media creatives;
- Determines operational feasibility by evaluating analysis, problem definition, requirements, solution development, and proposed solutions.
- Knowledge of computer systems and the latest technologies.
- Networking and setting up policy guidelines;
- Informs and trains staff on how to adhere to security ICT policies and train new and current employees on computer software and ICT systems
- Diagnose and resolve any security vulnerabilities related to hardware, software, or connectivity issues with minimal delays.
- Carry out the implementation of systems to guarantee the security and integrity of data.

## OCT 2020 - NOV 2020, PAPAYA CREATIVE, SOCIAL MEDIA

- Build and execute social media strategy through research, benchmarking, messaging, and audience identification;
- Write, develop, and strategize online content production and scheduling;
- Assist with crisis management, bad reviews, and negative news communications;
- Generate, edit, publish, and share content daily (original text, images, video, and HTML) Build meaningful connections and encourage community members through dialog and messaging;

#### **EDUCATION**

10/2016 - 08/2019, Abaarso-Tech University (ATU), Degree in Software Engineering 06/2012 - 06/2016, Nordin Boys High School, Higher School Certificate

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Monitoring completeness of forms for accuracy and consistency after the data collection.
- Checking the data quality, performance, and sampling protocols by accurately and strictly following the guide/survey tools used for the specific data collection.
- Maintaining working components through repair or replacement pf hardware and software tools;
- Ensuring that all systems are working properly and the timely delivery.;
- Performing basic computer hardware/software installation and configuration;
- Sustaining and guiding field staff using online communication platforms;
- Ability to communicate with the team and help them to troubleshoot any hardware and software errors;
- Oversee troubleshooting for system errors
- Provide helpdesk support for network issues
- Provide technical support either by phone, remote access, or site visits as needed
- Respond to IT issues; hardware maintenance, software, networking, etc.
- Evaluate connectivity issues, equipment, and software
- Design promotional materials for disseminating within the organization and throughout the country as well as external stakeholders;
- Document and report information required for program report analysis

### **CERTIFICATIONS & ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Successfully completed Y-Peer leadership and Volunteerism training
- Certificate of achievement of programming at Lynda training
- Certificate of achievement of operating systems (Windows, MacOSX, Linux OS).
- Certificate III in Information, Digital Media and Technology

## LANGAUGE PROFICIENCY

	Writing	Speaking	Reading	Listening
English		••		
Arabic				
Spanish				
Somali				

## REFRENCE

## **Mohamed Sugule**

Title: Admin/HR Officer Organization: Acted

Address: Jigjiga Area, Behind Mansoor Hotel, Hargeisa, Somaliland

Tel: +252 63 4234217

Email: hargeisa.administration@acted.org

Skype: Mohamed.sugule

## Symon Thuo

Title: AME Manager Organization: Acted

Address: Kalamu House, Grevillea Grove, off Brookside Dr, Nairobi, Kenya

Tel:+254 0724 026 906

Email: symon.thuo@acted.org

Skype: symon.thuo

### **Abdifatah Mouse**

Title: Web Developer

Organization: Aways Developers

Address: Rd Number 1, Near Alpha University, Hargiesa, Somaliland

Tel: +252 63 4856219

Email: cabdifataaxmuuse@gmail.com

Skype: @abdiftahMouse

### Filsan Mohamed

Title: Digital Marketing officer

Organization: Papaya Creative Group

Address: Rd Number 2, Ali Gobonimo Mall, Hargeisa, Somaliland

Tel: +252 63 4798042

Email: filsan@papayacreativegroup.com

FB: efilsan